<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The rates of marchandizes as they are set downe in the Booke of rates for the custome and subsidie of poundage, and for the custome and subsidie of cloathes, the same being appointed by his Maiestie, and confirmed by the Lorde deputye and Councell, and ordered to be published in print, for the direction of such as it may concerne in this kingdome of Ireland.</title>
            <title>Book of rates.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1608</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A04070</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 14128.3</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S113285</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99848521</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99848521</idno>
            <idno type="VID">13621</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A04070)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 13621)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1687:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The rates of marchandizes as they are set downe in the Booke of rates for the custome and subsidie of poundage, and for the custome and subsidie of cloathes, the same being appointed by his Maiestie, and confirmed by the Lorde deputye and Councell, and ordered to be published in print, for the direction of such as it may concerne in this kingdome of Ireland.</title>
                  <title>Book of rates.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Iohn Franckton, printer to the Kings most excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1608.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>A1 blank except for signature and decorative woodcut panel.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A-B⁴.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the University College (University of Oxford). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tariff --  Ireland --  Tables.</term>
               <term>Tariff --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:13621:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:13621:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:13621:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:13621:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
            <p>THE RATES OF MARCHANDI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ZES AS THEY ARE SET DOWNE in the Booke of Rates for the Cuſtome and <hi>Subsidie of Poundage, and for the Cuſtome and Subsi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die</hi> of Cloathes, the ſame being appointed by his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſtie, and Confirmed by the Lorde deputye and Councell, and ordered to be publiſhed in Print, for the direction of ſuch as it may concerne in this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome of <hi>Ireland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>DVBLIN.</hi> Printed by Iohn Franckton, Printer to the Kings <hi>moſt excellent Maieſtie.</hi> 1608.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="customs_rates">
            <pb facs="tcp:13621:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 19 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:13621:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 19 -->
            <head>BY THE LORD DEPVTIE AND <hi>COVNCELL.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas by an Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament made in the fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth yeer of the raigne of King Henry the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uenth of famous me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mory, it was at the pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er of the Commons or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained and eſtabliſhed<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> That the ſaid King &amp; his Heires ſhould haue, per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiue and leuie of all and euery xx. <abbr>s.</abbr> worth of all manner of Marchandize and Wares brought into this land of Ireland, by any manner of perſon or perſons, to be ſould within the ſame Land, twelue pence, and likewiſe ſhould haue, leuie and receaue of euery twentie ſhillings worth of all manner of Marchandize and Wares after the price that they be bought within this Land, and to bee carried out of the ſame, to be ſould by any manner of perſon or perſons beyond the Sea, twelue pence, as in the ſame Act among other things, more at large is contained;</p>
            <p>And foraſmuch as hitherto the Wares and Marchandizes out of which the ſaid poundage or twelue pence of the pound is to be raiſed, haue
<pb facs="tcp:13621:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 20 -->
had not certaine values or Rates ſet vppon them in this Kingdome, by reaſon whereof the ſaide Poundage or twelue pence of the pound hath not been truelie and fully aunſwered vnto the Kings moſt excellent Maieſtie, and his Progenitors;</p>
            <p>Wee haue therefore cauſed all the goods and Marchandizes chargeable with the ſaid poundage either broght in, or tranſported out of this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome, together with the ſeuerall kinds, qualities, numbers, weights, meaſures and contents of the ſame, and the values, prices, and Rates thereof to be particularly entred and expreſſed in this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Booke, containing in leaues on both ſides <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>to the entent his Maieſtie may henceforth bee iuſtly aunſwered of the ſaid poundage, according to the tenor of the ſaid Act of Parliament;</p>
            <p>Wherefore we do hereby declare &amp; publiſh his Highnes pleaſure &amp; comandment to be, That all his Maieſties Cuſtomers or Collectors of Cuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tomes or Subſidies within any Port, Hauen or Creeke of this his Highnes Realme of Ireland, for the tyme being ſhal from &amp; immediatly after no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice giuen by theſe preſents of his Highnes ſaid pleaſure, leauie and take vp to his Maieſties vſe the ſaid poundage or twelue pence vppon the pound, according to the priſes, values, &amp; rates me<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned <pb facs="tcp:13621:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 20 -->
and expreſſed in this Booke, &amp; not other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, as they and euery of them will aunſwere for the contrary, at their perills.</p>
            <p>Willing further, and hereby commaunding his Maieſties Threſurer &amp; Barons of the Eſchec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer of this Realme, and the ſaid Comptroullers and Surueyors for the tyme being, within anie Port, Hauen, or Creeke of this Realme of Ireland, and euerie of them, to charge the ſaid Collectors and Cuſtomers &amp; euery of them, to ſee his High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes duely aunſwered of the ſaid poundage, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the values, prices, and Rates, mentioned in this Booke, and none otherwiſe. Given at his Maieſties Caſtle of Dublin the xxiij day of Iune. 1608.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="abstract">
            <pb facs="tcp:13621:5"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 21 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:13621:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 21 -->
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> AN ABSTRACTE OF THE RATES OF THE MOST V<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuall Commodities of Ireland, ſet according to <hi>their valewes and worth, vpon view of a Coppie of the ſaide</hi> Rates receiued from thence, conferred by vs with the Booke of Rates for the Commodities of England, and is done by Order from the Lords and others of his Maieſties moſt Honourable Priuie Councell of England.</head>
            <div n="A" type="part">
               <head>A</head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Nniſeeds the C. weight, cont. fiue ſcore and twelue pound. xxx. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Allome the C. weight, cont. 112. pound xx. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="B" type="part">
               <head>B</head>
               <list>
                  <item>BAcon the Flitch, ii. <abbr>s.</abbr> vi. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Battery or Kettels the C. weight cont. one hundred &amp; twelue pound. iii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Braſſe Pottes the C. weight. iii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Beere the Tunne, xl. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <pb facs="tcp:13621:6"/>
                     <!-- PDF PAGE 22 -->Buffins, Moccadoes, Grogarines, and all ſuch Stuffes, as in Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</item>
                  <item>Butter the Barrell, i. <abbr>l.</abbr> vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="C" type="part">
               <head>C</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Cappes,
<list>
                        <item>Of Veluet the doſen i. <abbr>l.</abbr> x. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Of Cloath the doſen i. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Chequers of ſundrie colours, the Packe cont. iiii. C. yeards, vi. ſcore to the C. viii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cheeſe the C. weight, cont. 112. pound. vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Coles vocat. Sea-coles, the Chaulder, x. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Colme to burne Lyme the chaulder, vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Corne and Graine of all ſorts, to pay as in England, that is, Wheate the Quarter, cont. eight Buſhels, containing viii. gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lons to the Buſhel, ii. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>And euery Quarter of other Graine, as Rye, Barly, Malt, Oates, Beanes &amp; Peaſe, to pay xvi. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="F" type="part">
               <head>F</head>
               <list>
                  <pb facs="tcp:13621:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 22 -->
                  <item>Fiſh
<list>
                        <item>HErrings white and full the Barrell, x. <abbr>s,</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Salmon the Tunne, vi. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>All other ſorts of Fiſh to be rated as in England.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Furres,
<list>
                        <item>Martron skinnes the doſen ii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Otter skins the doſen i. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Foxe skinnes the doſen x. <abbr>s</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>All other ſorts as in England.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="G" type="part">
               <head>G</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Glaſſes of all ſortes, as in England.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="H" type="part">
               <head>H</head>
               <list>
                  <item>HIdes of Oxe or Cowe the peece v. <abbr>s</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hawkes of all ſortes, as in England.</item>
                  <item>Honney the Tunne, as in England.</item>
                  <item>Hoppes the C. weight, containing 112. pound i. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                     <list>
                        <item>Into England, the Horſe xiii. <abbr>l.</abbr> vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Horſes Into any other forraine part, the peece xx. <abbr>l.</abbr> x. <abbr>s</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="I" type="part">
               <head>I</head>
               <list>
                  <pb facs="tcp:13621:7"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 23 -->
                  <item>Iron the Tunne, vii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="L" type="part">
               <head>L</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Leade the Fodder or Tunne, vi. <abbr>l.</abbr> xiii. <abbr>s.</abbr> iiii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="M" type="part">
               <head>M</head>
               <list>
                  <item>MAnteling the Packe, cont. iiii. C. yeards, 120. to the hundred. xii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Manteling or Frizes the yeard. vi. <abbr>d</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mantells
<list>
                        <item>Of the beſt ſort the peece xiii. <abbr>s.</abbr> iiii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Of the worſt ſort the peece, vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="O" type="part">
               <head>O</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Oyle of all ſortes, as in England,</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="P" type="part">
               <head>P</head>
               <list>
                  <item>PEwter the C. weight cont. 112. pound. iii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Petticotes of Cotten the doſen ii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="R" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:13621:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 23 -->
               <head>R</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Rugges for Beds.
<list>
                        <item>THe beſt, i. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>All other ſortes the peece x. <abbr>s</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Blanketting Rugges the peece, v. <abbr>s</abbr>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="S" type="part">
               <head>S</head>
               <list>
                  <item>SAckecloath the peece, containing 15 yeards, i. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Saffron the pound, i. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Salte,
<list>
                        <item>Spaniſh the Wey, cont. 40. Buſhels, i. <abbr>l.</abbr> vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>French the Wey, cont. 40. Buſhells xx, <abbr>s,</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>white the wey co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. 40. Buſhels i. <abbr>l.</abbr> vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Silkes of all ſorts as in England,</item>
                  <item>Soape the Firkine x. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Soape Aſhes the C. weight iii. <abbr>s.</abbr> iiii. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Spices and Drugges of all ſorts, as in England.</item>
                  <item>Slates the thouſand vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Small Wares of all ſortes, as in England.</item>
                  <item>Skinnes, Lambe skinnes the C. cont. 120, white or blacke x, <abbr>s,</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mortkines rawe the C. cont 120 vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="T" type="part">
               <head>T</head>
               <list>
                  <pb facs="tcp:13621:8"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 24 -->
                  <item>TAllow &amp; Tallow Candles the C. weight, xx, <abbr>s,</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Timber
<list>
                        <item>The Tunne in great &amp; ſmall pecces vi, <abbr>s,</abbr> viii <abbr>d</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Pipe ſtaues the M. cont. ten C. 120 to the C. v. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Hogſhead-ſtaues the thouſand, xl. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Barrell Boords the thouſand xxx. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Inche Boords the C. foote, cont. 110. iii. <abbr>s.</abbr> iiii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Two Inche Boords the like C. foote vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Three Inche Boords or Planckes the like C. foote x. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                        </item>
                        <item>Foure Inche Planckes the like C. foote xiii. <abbr>s.</abbr> iiii. <abbr>d.</abbr>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Thread Blacke or Browne the Boult x. <abbr>s</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>All other ſorts of Thread as in England</item>
                  <item>Tynne the C. weight, cont. 112. pound liii. <abbr>s.</abbr> iiii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="W" type="part">
               <head>W</head>
               <list>
                  <item>VVAxe the C. weight, cont. 112. pound. iiii. <abbr>l.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>Wines of all ſorts, for Cuſtome and Subſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die, as in England</item>
                  <item>Woole of all ſortes, the Stone iiii. <abbr>s.</abbr>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <pb facs="tcp:13621:8" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <!-- PDF PAGE 24 -->Wollen cloath, and all Woollen Stuffes whatſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uer, as in England</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="Y" type="part">
               <list>
                  <item>YArne vocat. Iriſh Yarne, the hundred weight cont. 112. pound iii. <abbr>l.</abbr> vi. <abbr>s.</abbr> viii. <abbr>d</abbr>
                  </item>
               </list>
               <p>All other commodities which ſhall be ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther brought into or ſhipped forth of the Realme of Ireland, not being herein mentioned &amp; rated, ſhalbe valued as in the Booke of Rates made for the valuation of Marchandizes in England, &amp; ſhal paye cuſtome and Subſidie according to the ſame.</p>
               <p>And all other co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>modities whirh are not men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned herein, nor in the ſaid Booke of Rates for England, ſhal be valued according to their worth: and if the ſame be to be ſhipped forth, then to bee valued as the ſame coſt in that Kingdome, and if the ſame ſhall be brought in, then to be valued as it coſt at the place from whence the ſame was brought.</p>
               <p>All herein contained, is to be vnderſtood Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh money.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
